Preliminary Inventory to the Friedrich Katz Collection, 1919-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Friedrich Katz Collection,
1919-1945
XX241
Katz, Friedrich, collector
95 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box. (38.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings, notes, and pamphlets, relating to international relations, international economic conditions, the oil industry, domestic conditions in Croatia, Croatia's role in international relations, the history and condition of Jews throughout the world, and military operations during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Box 96 Closed due to unstable original documents. Use copies of all unstable originals are available.
Collection open for research.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Clippings, notes, and pamphlets, relating to international relations, international economic conditions, the oil industry, domestic conditions in Croatia, Croatia's role in international relations, the history and condition of Jews throughout the world, and military operations during World War II.
Arrangement
Arranged in seven groups. I: Politics and economics in the world (Politik und Wirtschaft in der Welt), II: Oil economics and policy (Erdörtschaft und Politik), III: Croatia (Kroatien), IV: The Jewish question (Judenfrage), V: World War II (Der 2. Weltkrieg), VI: Unsorted newspapers (Unsortierte Zeitungen) (Vöscher Beobachter, Deutsche Allgemeine Zeitung, u.a.), VII. Closed Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
International economic relations.; Jews.; Jews--History.; Petroleum industry and trade.; World politics.; World War, 1939-1945.; Croatia.; Yugoslavia.; Yugoslavia--History--1918-1945.
Container List
- I: Politics and economics in the world (Politik und Wirtschaft in der Welt), 1902-1948 (Box 1)
  - Asia-India (Asien–Indien), 1929-1940 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Africa (Afrika)
    - General (Allgemeines), 1942-1948 (Folder 1: 2)
    - North Africa (Nordafrika), 1933-1942 (Folder 1: 3)
    - West Africa (Westafrika), 1941-1942 (Folder 1: 4)
    - East Africa (Ostafrika), 1940-1942 (Folder 1: 5)
    - South Africa (Südafrika), 1937-1942 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Roosevelt's raids against Africa (Roosevelts Raubzüge gegen Afrika), 1942-1943 (Folder 1: 7-8)
    - Unsorted articles about Africa (Unsortierte verschiedene Artikel über Afrika), 1941-1944 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Near East (Der Nahe Osten) (Box 2)
    - Unsorted articles (Unsortierte Artikel), 1942-1944 (Folder 2: 1-2)
    - Abyssinia, Egypt, general, Arabia (Abessinien, Ägypten, Allgemeines, Arabien), 1928-1943 (Folder 2: 3-6)
    - Iraq, Iran, Syria, Jordan (Irak, Iran, Syrien, Transjordanien), 1928-1943 (Box-folder 3: 1-4)
    - Palestine(Palästina)
      - 1924-1937 (Folder 3: 5-7)
      - 1938-1943 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Europe (Europa)
    - Miscellany about economics and politics (Verschiedenes über Wirtschaft und Politik), 1941-1944 (Folder 4: 2-3)
    - Miscellaneous articles (Verschiedene Artikel), 1942 (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  - Das neue Europa, 1941-1943 (Folder 5: 3-4)
  - Russia (Russland) (Box 6)
    - Soviets and religion, politics, culture (Sowjets und Religion, Politik, Kultur), 1941-1943 (Folder 6: 1)
    - Unsorted articles (Verschiedene Artikel, unsortiert), 1926-1944 (Folder 6: 2-3)
  - England
    - Politics, general (Politik, Allgemeines), 1942-1943 (Folder 6: 4)
    - Politics and economics (Politik und Wirtschaft) (Box 7)
      - 1928-1937 (Folder 7: 1)
      - 1942 (Folder 7: 2)
    - Unsorted articles (Unsortierte Artikel), 1941-1944 (Folder 7: 3-4)
  - France (Frankreich), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
  - Belgium (Belgien), 1941-1943 (Folder 8: 3)
  - The Netherlands (Niederlande), 1941-1944 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Finland (Finnland), 1941-1944 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Norway (Norwegen), 1941-1944 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Sweden (Schweden), 1941-1944 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Denmark (Dänemark), 1928-1944 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Switzerland (Schweiz), 1942-1944 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Italy (Italien), 1942-1944 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
  - Portugal, 1941-1944 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Spain - The Iberian community (Spanien – Die iberische Gemeinsamkeit), 1941-1944 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Greece - Bulgaria (Griechenland – Bulgarien), 1943-1944 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Anglo-American currency plans (Anglo-Amerikanische Währungspläne), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Atlantic Charter - The entire program of 17 points (Die Atlantik-Charta – Das Hullprogramm der 17 Punkte), 1942-1944 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Emigrants (Emigranten), 1943 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Germany (Deutschland)
    - Obituaries for (Todesnachrichten über) Friedrich Ebert, M. v. Baden, Gustav Stresemann, Vikt. Zubkow, Georges Clemenceau, Zencker, Borsig, Böhm, Wilhelm Cuno, 1925-1933 (Folder 11: 4)
    - Non-German history (Ausserdeutsche Geschichte), 1928-1942 (Folder 11: 5-6)
    - Wir und die Welt - Miscellaneous articles (Verschiedene Artikel), 1939—1943 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Greater Germany (Grossdeutschland)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1941-1943 (Folder 12: 2)
      - Politics (Politik), 1938-1943 (Folder 12: 3)
      - Economics - General (Wirtschaft – Allgemeines), 1942-1943 (Folder 12: 4)
      - Industry and agriculture (Industrie und Landwirtschaft), 1942-1943 (Folder 12: 5)
      - The German "Gaue" (Die deutschen Gaue), 1941-1943 (Folder 12: 6)
      - Districts and cities (Landschaften und Städte), 1942-1943 (Folder 12: 7)
      - Protectorate and General Gouvernement (Protektorat und General Gouvernement), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - History, Middle Ages to modern times, cultural history, art (Geschichte, Mittelalter bis Neuzeit, Kulturgeschichte, Kunst), 1902-1943 (Folder 13: 2-3)
  - America, South America, Argentina - politics, economics, culture (Amerika, Südamerika, Argentinien - Politik, Wirtschaft, Kultur), 1928-1943 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
- II: Oil economics and policy (Erdölwirtschaft und Politik), 1900-1929
  - Oil in Germany(Erdöl in Deutschland)
    - Oil territories (Erdölgebiete), 1926-1928 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Oil output (Erdölgebiete), 1926-1927
    - Synthetic oils (Synthetische Öle), 1927
    - Oil companies (Erdölgesellschaften), 1928-1929
    - Oil share to German market (Der Anteil des Erdöls am deutschen Handel), 1924-1928
    - Oil supply agreements (Erdöllieferungsverträge, 1928
    - Miscellany (Vermischtes), 1928
    - Market reports (Marktberichte), 1928
    - Transportation and costs (Transporte und Transportpreise), 1928
    - Foreign penetration in the German oil industry (Ausländisches Eindringen in die deutsche Erdölindustrie), 1928
    - Price war on the German market (Preiskampf am deutschen Markt), 1928
    - Development of the oil industry in Germany (Die Entwicklung der Erdölindustrie in Deutschland), 1928-1929
    - Germany's oil consumption (Deutschlands Erdölverbrauch), 1928
  - Oil producer and consumer nations (Erdölproduktion und Konsumländer)
    - Egypt (Ägypten), 1911-1922 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Argentina (Argentinien), 1922-1928
    - Australia (Australien), 1928
    - Belgium (Belgien), 1927-1928
    - Bolivia (Bolivien), 1922-1928
    - Brasil (Brasilien), 1926-1928
    - British India (Britisch-Indien), 1922-1928
    - Bulgaria (Bulgarien), 1927-1928
    - Chile, 1926-1928
    - China, 1913-1922
    - German Austria (Deutsch-Österreich), 1926-1929 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - England, 1914-1929
    - Estonia (Estland), 1927-1929
    - France (Frankreich), 1927-1929
    - Greece (Griechenland), 1926
    - Italy (Italien), 1927
    - Japan, 1921-1928
    - Yugoslavia (Jugoslawien), 1922-1928
    - Canada (Kanada), 1913-1928
    - Colombia (Kolumbien), 1922-1928
    - Cuba (Kuba), 1927
    - Latvia (Lettland), 1927-1928
    - Lithuania (Litauen), 1927
    - Mesopotamia (Mesopotamien), 1922-1928 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Mexico, 1922-1928
    - Netherlands Indies (Niederländisch-Indien), 1922
    - Norway (Norwegen), 1928
    - Persia (Persien), 1922-1929
    - Peru, 1922-1928
    - Poland (Polen), 1922-1929 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Romania (Rumälnien), 1900-1929
    - Russia (Russland), 1912-1929 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Oil territories (Erdölgebiete), 1914-1928
    - Russia (Russland), 1927-1929 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Oil companies (Erdölgesellschaften), 1927-1929
    - Russia (Russland), 1928 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Oil policy and supply agreements (Erdöl-Politik und Lieferungsverträge), 1926-1928
    - Russia (Russland), 1927-1928 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Capital deficiencies and procurement, concessions (Kapitalmangel und -beschaffung, Konzessionen u.a.), 1926-1929
    - Sweden (Schweden), 1928 (Folder 16: 4)
    - Spain (Spanien), 1927-1929
    - South Africa (Südafrika), 1927
    - Trinidad, 1928
    - Czechoslovakia (Tschechoslowakei), 1927-1928
    - Turkey (Türkei), 1927-1928
    - Hungary (Ungarn), 1927-1928
    - Uruguay, 1926-1927
    - Venezuela, 1926-1928 (Folder 16: 5)
    - United States of America (Vereinigte Staaten von Nordamerika), 1927-1929
  - Oil battles (Erdölkämpfe) (Box 17)
    - Different countries (Verschiedene Länder), 1927-1928 (Folder 17: 1)
    - Russia (Russland), 1926-1928 (Folder 17: 2)
  - International oil negotiations (Internationale Erdölverhandlungen), 1928-1929 (Folder 17: 3)
  - Oil statistics (Erdöl-Statistik), 1926-1929 (Folder 17: 4)
  - Synthetic oil (Synthetisches Öl), 1928 (Folder 17: 5)
  - Oil (Erdöl)
    - Miscellany (Vermischtes), 1922-1928 (Folder 17: 6)
    - General development of the world oil industry (Allgemeine Entwicklung der Welterdölindustrie u.a.), 1927-1928
    - Miscellany (Vermischtes), 1926-1928 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Extraction and quality of oil (Gewinnung und Qualität des Öls), 1927-1928
    - Pricing (Preisgestaltung u.a.), 1926-1928
  - Oil (Erdöl)
    - Anglo-Persian Oil Co., 1922-1929 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Royal Dutch Shell Trust, 1913-1929
    - Standard Oil Co., 1903-1929 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Oil companies and territories (Erdölgesellschaften und Gebiete) (Box 19)
      - Aa-As, 1926-1928 (Folder 19: 1)
      - At-Az und B, 1927-1928 (Folder 19: 2)
      - C, 1928 (Folder 19: 3)
      - D, 1928 (Folder 19: 4)
      - E, F, G, 1926-1928 (Folder 19: 5)
      - H, J, K, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 20: 1)
      - L, M, 1926-1928 (Folder 20: 2)
      - N, 1926-1928 (Folder 20: 3)
      - O, P, 1915-1928 (Folder 20: 4)
      - Q, R, 1927-1928 (Folder 20: 5)
      - Sa-Sm, 1928 (Folder 20: 6)
      - Sn-Sz, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 21: 1)
      - T, 1928 (Folder 21: 2)
      - U, 1926-1927 (Folder 21: 3)
      - V-Z, 1926-1928 (Folder 21: 4)
    - Miscellaneous articles about oil questions (Verschiedene über Erdölfragen), 1928-1930 (Folder 21: 5-6)
    - Miscellaneous articles about general economical questions (Verschiedene Artikel über allgemeine Wirtschaftsfragen), 1926-1939 (Folder 21: 7-8)
    - Collection of single writings about oil (Sammlung von Einzelschriften über Erdöl) 15 articles and 50 single booklets by (15 Artikel und 50 Einzelhefte von) Dr. Karl Hoffman, Dr. Fritz Nonnenbruch, Dr. Karl Krüger, Wolfram Doellen, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 22: 1)
- III: Croatia (Kroatien), 1910-1944 (Box 23)
  - Southeast Europe (Südost-Europa)
    - General (Allgemeines), 1940-1944 (Folder 23: 1-2)
    - Yugoslavia (Jugoslawien), 1936-1944 (Folder 23: 3-4)
    - The Jewish question (Judenfrage), 1942-1944
    - Albania (Albanien), 1910-1944 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
    - Dalmatia (Dalmatien), 1941-1944
    - Montenegro, 1941-1944
    - Serbia (Serbien), 1941-1944 (Folder 24: 3-4)
    - Slovakia (Slowakei), 1938-1944
    - Bulgaria (Bulgarien), 1941-1944 (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
    - Greece (Griechenland), 1941-1944
    - Romania (Rumänien), 1941-1944 (Folder 25: 3-4)
    - Hungary (Ungarn), 1941-1944 (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
  - The face of the Balkans (Das Gesicht des Balkans), 1941-1944 (Box 27)
    - Tradition (Brauchtum) (Folder 27: 1-2)
    - Traditional costumes (Trachten)
    - Art (Kunst)
    - Architecture (Bauweise)
  - Croatia (Kroatien), 1941-1944
    - History (Geschichte) (Folder 27: 3)
    - Derivation (Abstammung)
    - Language (Sprache)
    - Tradition (Volkstum)
    - War history to 1941 (Kriegsgeschichte bis 1941), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 28: 1-2)
    - Participation in World War II (Teilnahme am 2. Weltkrieg), 1941-1943
    - Campaign against gangs (Bandenbekämpfung), 1942-1944
    - New foundation of the state – prehistory (Staatsneugründung – Vorgeschichte)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 28: 3)
      - 1942-1943
      - 1943-1944
    - State borders (Staatsgrenzen), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - The king (Der König), 1941-1943
    - Der Poglavnik, 1941-1942
    - Ministries (Ministerien), 1941-1943
    - State celebrations (Staatsfeiern), 1941-1942
    - Croatians abroad (Auslandskroatentum), 1941-1943 (Folder 29: 2)
    - Minorities (Völkische Minderheiten), 1941-1943
    - Return migration (Rückwanderung), 1942-1943
    - Foreign policy (Aussenpolitik)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1941-1944 (Folder 29: 3)
      - Germany (Deutschland), 1941-1942
      - Italy (Italien), 1941-1942
      - Japan, 1941-1942
      - Participation in war (Teilnahme am Krieg), 1941-1944
      - Bulgaria (Bulgarien), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - Montenegro, 1941
      - Romania (Rumänien), 1942
      - Slovakia (Slowakei), 1941-1942
      - Hungary (Ungarn), 1942
      - West Europe (West–Europa), 1941-1942
      - East Europe (Ost–Europa), 1941-1942
      - Non-European countries (Aussereuropäische Länder), 1941
    - Domestic policy (Innenpolitik)
      - Sabor, 1942 (Folder 30: 2)
      - Ustascha, 1941-1942
      - Constitution and laws (Verfassung und Gesetze), 1942
      - Police (Polizei), 1942-1943
      - Wehrmacht, 1942
      - Administration of justice (Rechtspflege), 1941-1942 (Folder 30: 3)
      - State church (Staatskirche), 1941-1942
      - Judaism and freemasonry (Judentum und Freimaurerei), 1941-1942
      - Social constitution (Sozialer Aufbau), 1941-1942 (Folder 30: 4)
      - Arbeitsdienst, 1941-1942
      - Classification of professions and education (Berufsgliederung und Ausbildung), 1942
      - Public officials and employees (Beamte und Angestellte), 1941-1942
      - Laborer (Arbeiter), 1941-1942
      - Fee and price policy (Lohn- und Preispolitik), 1941-1942
      - Public works (Öffentliche Arbeiten), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      - Domestic colonization (Innere Kolonisation), 1942
      - Monopolies (Monopole), 1941-1942
      - Zagreb (Agram), 1941-1942
      - Banja Luka, 1941-1942
      - Chambers of engineering (Ingenieurskammern), 1941-1942
      - Decorations (Orden und Ehrenzeichen), 1942
      - National budget (Staatshaushalt), 1942 (Folder 31: 2)
      - Taxes, tolls (Steuern, Zölle), 1941-1942
      - Currency (Währung, Devisen), 1941-1942
      - Financial policy (Finanzpolitik), 1941-1942
      - Charging agreement (Verrechnungsabkommen), 1941-1942
      - State bank (Staatsbank), 1941-1942
      - Capital market (Kapitalmarkt), 1941-1942
      - Capital abroad (Auslandskapital), 1941-1942
      - Banks (Banken), 1941-1942
      - Stock exchange (Börse), 1941-1942
      - Savings banks (Sparkassen), 1941-1942
      - Cooperatives (Genossenschaften), 1941-1942
      - Insurance (Versicherungen), 1941-1942
      - Liabilities of Yugoslavia (Jugoslawische Schulden), 1941-1942
      - Traffic system – general (Verkehrswesen – Allgemeines), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - Railroad (Eisenbahn), 1941-1942
      - Rates (Tarife), 1941-1942
      - Roads and Highways (Land- und Autostrassen), 1941-1942
      - Waterways (Wasserstrassen), 1941-1942
      - Air traffic (Flugverkehr), 1941-1942
      - Seafaring (Seefahrt), 1941-1942
      - Harbors (Häfen), 1941
      - The heritage of Yugoslavia (Jugoslawisches Erbe), 1941-1942
      - Post – general (Allgemeines), 1941-1942 (Folder 32: 2)
      - Die Post, 1941-1942
      - Telephones (Fernsprecher), 1941-1942
      - Telegraphs (Telegraf), 1942
      - Packages (Paketverkehr), 1942
    - Communication (Nachrichtenwesen)
      - Newspapers (Presse), 1941-1942 (Folder 32: 3)
      - Radio broadcast (Rundfunk), 1941-1942
      - Film, 1941-1942
      - Traveling and spas (Reisen und Bäder), 1941-1942
      - Sports (Sport), 1941-1942
    - Sciences (Wissenschaften) (Box 33)
      - Croatia's cultural relations to foreign countries (Kroatiens Kulturbeziehungen zum Ausland), 1941-1942 (Folder 33: 1)
      - Universities (Hochschulen), 1941-1942 (Folder 33: 2)
    - Art history (Kunstgeschichte)
      - Painting and sculpture (Malerei und Bildhauerei), 1941-1942 (Folder 33: 3)
      - Museums, theatre, music (Museen, Theater, Musik), 1941-1942
    - History of literature (Literaturgeschichte) (Box 34)
      - Literature of Croatia (Kroatisches Schrifttum), 1941-1942 (Folder 34: 1)
      - Folk poetry (Volksdichtung), 1941-1942
    - Economy (Wirtschaft)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1941-1942 (Folder 34: 2)
      - Organization and management of the economy (Wirtschaftsorganisation und –lenkung), 1941-1942
      - Economic police (Wirtschaftspolizei), 1941-1942
      - Price policy (Preispolitik), 1941-1942 (Folder 34: 3)
      - Price ceilings (Höchstpreise), 1941-1942
    - Agriculture (Landwirtschaft) (Box 35)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1941-1942 (Folder 35: 1)
      - Soil (Boden), 1942
      - Cultivation (Anbau), 1942
      - Seeds (Saatgut), 1942
      - Grain (Getreide), 1941
      - Corn, hemp, flax (Mais, Hanf, Flachs), 1941-1942
      - Turnips (Rüben), 1941-1942
      - Potatoes (Kartoffeln), 1942
      - Oil plants (Ölpflanzen), 1942
      - Vegetables (Gemüse), 1942
      - Fruits (Obst), 1941-1942
      - Wine (Wein), 1941-1942
      - Tobacco (Tabak), 1941-1942
      - Chicory (Zichorie), 1941-1942
      - Cotton (Baumwolle), 1941-1942
      - Animal feed (Futtermittel), 1942
      - Hothouse (Treibhäuser), 1942
      - Mills (Mühlen), 1941-1942 (Folder 35: 2)
      - Silos, 1941-1942
      - Fruit dehydration (Obst-Dörren), 1942
      - Cans (Konserven), 1942
      - Engines (Maschinen), 1942
      - Monopolies (Monopole), n.d.
      - Insurance (Versicherung), 1942
      - Harvest survey (Ernte-Erfassung), 1941-1942
      - Constraint of contributions (Ablieferungszwang), 1941-1942
      - Takeover prices (Öbernahmepreise), 1941-1942
      - Premiums (Prämien), 1942
      - Harvest protection (Ernteschutz), 1942
      - Harvest report (Erntebericht), 1941
      - Statistics (Statistik), 1942
    - Stock farming, Forestry, timber industry, and hunting (Viehzucht, Forst–und Holzwirtschaft, Jagd)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1941-1942 (Folder 35: 3)
      - Horse breeding (Pferdezucht), 1941-1942
      - Cattle breeding (Rinderzucht)
      - Pig breeding (Schweinezucht), 1942
      - Sheep breeding (Schafzucht), 1942
      - Rabbit keeping (Kaninchenzucht), n.d.
      - Poultry farming (Geflügelzucht), 1941-1942
      - Bee keeping (Bienenzucht), 1942
      - Fish farming (Fischzucht), 1941-1942
      - Oyster farming (Austernzucht), 1942
      - Forestry (Forstwirtschaft), 1941-1942
      - Timber industry (Holzwirtschaft), 1942
      - Hunting (Jagd), 1942
    - Industry (Industrie)
      - Soaps (Seifen), 1941-1942 (Folder 35: 4)
      - Metal (Metall), 1941-1942
      - Textile (Textil), 1941-1942
      - Paper (Papier), 1941-1942
      - Bauxite (Bauxit), 1941-1942
    - Trading (Handel), 1941-1942 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - Directives of Croatia's trading policy (Richtlinien der kroatischen Handelspolitik), 1941-1942
    - Foreign trading policy (Aussenhandel), 1941-1942 (Folder 36: 2)
    - Trading agreements and economic negotiations (Handelsabkommen und Wirtschaftsverhandlungen), 1941-1942
    - Trade fairs in Zagreb (Agramer Messen), 1941-1942
    - Companion reports (Gesellschaftsberichte), 1941-1943 (Folder 36: 3)
    - Industry and banks (Industrie und Banken), 1941-1943
    - Miscellaneous articles (Verschiedene Artikel) (Box 37)
      - Economy (über die kroatische Wirtschaft u.a.), 1941-1943 (Folder 37: 1-2)
      - Freight traffic, trading agreements, the Danube conference in Vienna, etc. (über Frachten- und Güterverkehr, Handelsabkommen, Wiener Donaukonferenz u.a.), 1941-1943 (Folder 37: 3)
      - Freight traffic, trading agreements, the Danube conference in Vienna, etc. (über Frachten- und Güterverkehr, Handelsabkommen, Wiener Donaukonferenz u.a.), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 38: 1)
      - The harvest, the cooperative system, the grain monopoly, the corporate organization in Croatia, etc. (über Kroatiens Ernte, Genossenschaftswesen Getreidemonopol, korporativer Aufbau u.a.), 1942-1944 (Folder 38: 2-3)
      - Organized dairy farming, the economy control, peasants in Croatia, education of peasants, etc. (über organisierte Milchwirtschaft, Wirtschaftskontrolle, kroatisches Bauerntum, Schulung der Bauern u.a.), n.d. (Box-folder 39: 1-3)
      - Architecture, sculpture and painting, lyrics and folk art (ferner: Bauweise, Bildhauerei und Malerei, Lyrik und Volkskunst), 1942-1944
  - Neue Ordnung (Box 40)
    - Weekly journal of Croatia about European politics, economy and culture (Kroatische Wochenschrift för europäische Politik, Wirtschaft und Kultur), 1943-1944 (Folder 40: 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous articles about Croatia and southeast Europe (Verschiedene Artikel öber Kroatien und Södost-Europa)
      - 1943-1944
      - 1944 (Box-folder 41: 1-2)
      - 1944 (Box-folder 42: 1)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 42: 2-3)
- IV: The Jewish question (Die Judenfrage), 1867-1944 (Box 43)
  - History (Geschichte)
    - General (Allgemeines), 1917-1926. (Folder 43: 1)
      Includes Der Antisemitismus: Eine Rassenlüge by Adolf Sommerfeld, 1917; Neue jüdische Monatshefte, 1919; and Berlin oder Juste Milieu by Carl Eternbeim, 1920
      - Antiquity (Altertum), 1917-1919
      - To 70 A.D. (bis 70 n. Chr.), 1925-1926
      - Jews in the Roman Empire to Constantine (Die Juden im römischen Weltreich bis Konstantin), n.d.
    - Europe (Europa)
      - Russia with riparian states, except Poland (Russland mit Randstaaten ohne Polen), 1920-1926 (Folder 43: 2)
      - Austria, also Hungary and Bohemia (Österreich, auch Ungarn und Böhmen), 1923-1924
      - Hungary (Ungarn), 1925
      - Romania (Rumänien), 1923-1926
      - Czechoslovakia (Tschechoslowakei), 1923
      - Poland (Polen), 1926
      - Bulgaria (Bulgarien), 1922-1925
      - Denmark (Dänemark), 1921
      - Spain (Spanien), n.d. (Folder 43: 3)
      - France (Frankreich), 1920-1924
      - England, 1921-1922
      - Holland/Belgium (Belgien), 1922
      - Italy (Italien), 1915-1924
    - Germany (Deutschland)
      - General (Allgemeines), 1922-1926 (Folder 43: 4)
      - Das deutsche Reich, 1922-1924
      - Berlin, 1912-1925
      - Bavaria (Bayern), 1919
      - Brandenburg-Prussia (Preuβen)
      - Baden, n.d.
      - Mecklenburg, n.d.
      - Saxony (Sachsen), n.d.
      - Kurhessen, n.d.
      - Thuringia (Thüringen), 1924
      - Hamburg-Lübeck-Bremen, 1922
      - Frankfurt/Main, 1922
      - General, thereunder "The Jewish Way to fight" (Verschiedenes, darunter "Jüdische Kampfesweise"), 1919-1924 (Folder 43: 5)
      - Jewish clubs in Germany (Judenvereine in Deutschland), 1919-1926
      - Jewish parties (Judenparteien)
        - Democrats (Demokraten), 1915-1924 (Folder 43: 6)
        - Center (Zentrum), 1923-1924
        - Unions (Gewerkschaften), 1923
        - General (Allgemeines über Judenparteien), 1920-1924 (Box-folder 44: 1)
        - U.S.P.D. – Communists (Kommunisten), 1918-1921